JOE PARSONS: So, I'm thinking about getting a puzzle.
LES MCGEHEE: Really?
I was reviewing the other day how my mortgage was advertising... JOE PARSONS: Uh-huh.
Hey, it's Les McGehee from "Les McGehee Plays Well With Others."
My name's on there because I wrote that book and it's about improvisation and about having a lengthy career with a lot of miles in the improvisation arts.
Along the way, I was lucky enough to meet Joe Parsons who may not look so funny now, but he really is.
Believe me, you'll have to take my word for it.
Now, Joe and I, we're going to try a few improv games for you right here and these aren't entertainment games.
These are games that we play with each other before shows, just to warm up and get in the frame of mind, and everybody get together before we do a show.
The first one we're going to try that is a simple one.
This is a great one that you can play with your family and friends in the car, and it helps to get your mind working.
We call it "Things In."
Joe, you want to start a "Things in?"
Explain to these people?
JOE PARSONS: Sure.
All right, Les, I wonder if you can name for me 5 things in your backyard.
LES MCGEHEE: A swing set.
JOE PARSONS: One.
LES MCGEHEE: A dog with red hair.
JOE PARSONS: Two.
LES MCGEHEE: A hole in the fence that needs to patched.
JOE PARSONS: Three.
LES MCGEHEE: A large amount of Jalapeno peppers and lemons on the vine.
JOE PARSONS: Four.
LES MCGEHEE: And a lemon tree because lemons don't grow on vines.
JOE PARSONS: Five, very nice.
LES MCGEHEE: You see how that works and now I can issue him a challenge as well.
And one thing to remember is that if you have a creative idea that feels funny to you, you use it.
And anytime you don't feel inspired by an idea, just call the thing whatever it is.
There's grass in my backyard.
And this way, you're accepting inspiration when it comes, but you don't feel any pressure.
You just maintain the game and inspiration comes again when it's ready to, and that helps to support everybody's creations at the same time.
What are 3 things in Dolly Parton's handbag, Joe?
JOE PARSONS: Kleenex, lipstick, and a brassiere.
LES MCGEHEE: What are 5 things Bozo the Clown won't be in the same room with?
JOE PARSONS: Barbara Bush, a Buick, a giant tub of Red Vines licorice.
LES MCGEHEE: Ooh.
JOE PARSONS: Plastic forks and a tree that grows purple fruit.
LES MCGEHEE: That is absolutely correct, Joseph, and you don't win anything.
But it was really funny and correct.
Now, you notice, whatever he says would have been correct because I'm not here to judge him, I'm here to play with him.
You have plenty of time to judge things in your life, that's a grown-up thing we all have to do, but we're not doing that now, we're just playing.